DAN KLEIN: So what's a CSP?
Well, in a standard search problem,
the state is a black box.
This is actually the beauty
of a search algorithm like
uniform cost search.
You don't care whether your state
is a pair of integers, or
a string, or what.
You don't care.
All you need to know is that you have
these things called states, there's
some arbitrary data structure that
encodes whatever that problem's doing
and you don't care.
The goal test is just some function over
states that give you a thumbs up
when you find a goal.
And then you have a successor function,
which is also just some
function that takes a state
returns its neighbors.
OK.
So the idea here is really in a standard
search problem, you've got
this judge at the end.
It's the goal test.
And it looks at a state, and it
says yes, this is a goal, no,
this is not a goal.
OK.
A constraint satisfaction problem kind
of peers into that black box a little.
And a constraint satisfaction problem,
it's still a search problem, but it's
a special kind of search problem where
we make assumptions about what exactly
goes into a state
In a CSP, the state is designed by a set
of variables that take on values.
The values come from what's
called a domain.
Sometimes there's one domain for all
the variables, sometimes there's a
domain for each variable.
So a state is a set of variables
that take on values.
And the goal test, rather than being
some arbitrary function, is now a set
of constraints that tell you what
combination of values are allowed on
different subsets of variables.
And we'll see a bunch of
examples of this today.
One example we'll look at is map
coloring, and the idea is you're
trying to find some assignment to your
variables that obey the constraints.
And you can imagine you've got here,
instead of just a judge at the end
that's stamping you thumbs up or thumbs
down, you've now got a handbook
that says if you want to satisfy the
constraints, here are the list of
rules you have to obey.
This is our first example in this
class of what's called a formal
representation language.
So in the real world, if you have a CSP
solver, very often the solver is
fully compiled, and you interact with
it purely through some declarative
specification of your constraints.
So you write down your constraints, some
computation happens, and out pops
your answer.
And that's a very powerful thing.
In addition, the fact that we can peer
into the CSP state and it's not just
some black box that supports the goal
function, but rather it's a collection
of variables and constraints, it
lets us improve our algorithms.
So we have algorithms that are still
general purpose in the sense that
they'll run on any CSP.
But they're much more powerful than
standard search algorithms.
And in particular, we'll see today why
a standard search algorithm is a poor
choice for the case of a CSP.